Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/hitesh-c-36359521b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

PHP

Laravel

React.js

Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate

Hitesh Chitalia

Senior PHP/Laravel/Vue Developer Delmar

Summary

I am a highly skilled and very language-flexible web developer with 7+ yrs of experience in responsive web development with PHP, Laravel, Vue, React, Angular, Node, Express, Next, Tailwind, Material, Bootstrap, RESTful API, GraphQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, etc. My work experience runs the gamut of software development, from software architecture, database design to website/webapp development.

Tech Stacks:

- PHP, Laravel, Symfony, Yii
- Vue, React, Angular, Next, Node, Express, Tailwind, Material, Bootstrap, jQuery
- RESTful API, GraphQL, 3rd party API integration
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

I am a proven troubleshooter who works well with other team members and I have worked with Agile Development, building test-driven code both as a developer and as a scrum master. In my personal life, I enjoy spending time with friends and family, as well as almost any outdoor activity.

Experience

Perpetual:

Full-stack Web Developer (Laravel, Vue, React, Node) 2018 - 2021 (3 years)

Nyack, New York, United States

- Was able to test, and implement swagger UI docs/routes, for front-end use and back-end development
- Used RESTful API to put the data as time series and tabular format for local timestamp data manipulation and retrieval and storing it into PostgreSQL.
- Used Fast API, and some request library/decorators for faster development.

 Used AWS cloud desktop, for daily jobs, and Brazil Build for Cloud environment.

Techneeds

Senior Web Developer (Laravel, Yii, Symfony, Vue, Angular, React) July 2017 - June 2019 (2 years)

Hopewell, New Jersey, United States

- Designed and Developed SQL database structure with Laravel Framework using agile methodology.
- Developed project using Laravel, Vue, Oracle, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React.js, Express.js and Bootstrap.
- Used Fast API to dispatch front end JSON type schema, along with PHP/ SQL, for delivery of sql, csv files, and using mysql db.
- Involved in the complete Software Development Life Cycle including gathering Requirements, Analysis, Design, Implementation, Testing and Maintenance.
- Used PHPUnit for unit testing, and verification of functionality, during the beta phase of development.

Saffron Technology, an Intel company Web Developer (PHP, Laravel, Vue, Angular) 2014 - 2016 (2 years)

Fairfield, New Jersey, United States

- Developed views and templates with PHP and Laravel's view controller and templating language to create a user-friendly Website interface.
- Managed datasets using Panda data frames and Oracle-SQL, queried
 Oracle-SQL database queries from python using PHP-Oracle-SQL connector
 and Oracle-SQL db package to retrieve information.
- Taken part in software development life cycle (SDLC) of the tracking systems Requirements, Gathering, Analysis, Detail Design, Development, System Testing and User Acceptance Testing.
- Created Restful API's to integrate and enhance functionalities of the application.

Five Jars
Software Engineer (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
2012 - 2013 (1 year)
Brooklyn, New York, United States

- Implemented user interface guidelines and standards throughout the development and maintenance of the Website using the HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery and VueJs.
- Design, involved in code reviews and wrote unit tests in PHP and Updated site with JavaScript, JQuery, Yii, Symfony, and SQL.
- Helped with the creation of a RESTful API using PHP-Laravel, integrating with Apache.

Education

Fordham University

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Computer Science · (2006 - 2011)